the following is a conversation with
以下是与之对话
Thomas sent home he's a professor same
托马斯送回家，他是 同 一个教授
you and co-creator of lebra's which is
你是lebra的共同创造者
the first AI system to be top human
第一个成为顶级人类的人工智能系统
players in the game of heads-up No Limit
单挑无限游戏中的玩家
Texas Hold'em he has published over 450
德州扑克他 发表了超过450个
papers on game theory and machine
关于博弈论和机器的论文
learning including a best paper in 2017
学习包括2017年的最佳论文
at nips now renamed to new reps which is
在nips 现在改名为新的代表
where I caught up with him for this
在那里我为此追上了他
conversation his research and companies
谈论 他的研究和公司
have had wide reaching impact in the
在这方面有广泛的影响
real world especially because he and his
现实世界特别是因为他和他
group not only proposed new ideas but
小组不仅提出了新的想法，而且
also build systems to prove that these
还建立系统来证明这些
ideas work in the real world
想法在现实世界中起作用
this conversation is part of the MIT
这次谈话是麻省理工学院的一部分
course on artificial general
人工将军课程
intelligence and the artificial
智力和人工
intelligence podcast if you enjoy
智能播客， 如果你喜欢
subscribe on youtube itunes or simply
订阅 youtube itunes 或简单
connect with me on Twitter at Lex
在 Lex的 Twitter上与我联系
Friedman spelled Fri D and now here's my
弗里德曼拼写了Fri D，现在这里是我的
conversation with Thomas sent home can
与托马斯的谈话送回家可以
you describe at the high level the game
你在高层描述游戏
of poker Texas Hold'em heads-up Texas
得克萨斯扑克德州扑克单挑德克萨斯州
Hold'em for people who might not be
德州扑克的人谁可能不是
familiar at this card game yeah happy to
熟悉这个纸牌游戏，我很高兴
so heads up No Limit Texas Hold'em has
所以德州扑克无限注德州扑克
really emerged in the AI community as a
真正出现在AI社区中的一个
main benchmark for testing these
测试这些的主要基准
application independent algorithms for
应用程序独立算法
imperfect information game solving and
不完善的信息游戏解决方案
this is a game that's actually played by
这是一个真正玩过的游戏
humans you don't see that much on TV or
人类你 在 电视 或 电视 上看不到 那么多
casinos because well for obvious reasons
赌场因为明显的原因
but you do see it in some expert level
但你确实在 一些专家级别 看到它
casinos and you see it in the best poker
赌场，你在最好的扑克中看到它
movies of all time it's actually an
有史以来的电影实际上是一部电影
event in the World Series of Poker but
世界扑克锦标赛中的比赛但是
mostly it's played online and typically
主要是它的在线和通常扮演
for pretty big sums of money and this is
对于相当大的钱，这是
a game that usually only experts play so
通常只有专家才能玩 的游戏
if you recall to your home game on a
如果你还记得你的主场比赛 上
Friday night it probably is not gonna be
星期五晚上它 可能 不会
hits up no Limit Texas Hold'em it might
它可能会打不限德州扑克
be no let me it takes us Hold'em in some
不要让我 拿着Hold'em
cases but typically for a big group and
案件，但通常 是一个大集团和
it's not as competitive well heads up
这不像竞争对手那么好
means it's two-player so it's really
意味着它是双人游戏，所以它真的
like me against you
像我一样反对你
Am I
我 是
you better much like chess or or or go
你最好像国际象棋或者或者去
in that sense but an imperfect
在这个意义上，但不完美
information game which makes it much
信息游戏，使它更多
harder because I have to deal with
更难， 因为我必须处理
issues of you knowing things that I
你 知道我的事情的 问题
don't know and I know things that you
不知道，我知道你的事情
don't know
不知道
instead of pieces being nicely laid on
而不是很好地铺设的碎片
the board for both of us to see
董事会让我们俩见
so in Texas Hold'em there's a two cards
所以在Texas Hold'em中有 两张牌
that you only see the game on to you
你只看到 游戏给你
yeah there is they gradually lay out
是的，他们逐渐 布局
some cards that add up overall to five
一些卡 总共 加起来 五个
cards that everybody can see yeah the
每个人都能看到的卡片是的
imperfect nature of the information is
信息的不完善性 是
the two cards that you're holding on
你持有的两张 牌
front yeah so as you said you know you
前面是的， 所以你说你 认识你
first get two cards in private each and
首先 私下 拿两张卡片
then you this a betting round then you
然后你这一轮下注然后你
get three clubs in public on the table
在桌子上公开三个俱乐部
then there's a betting round then you
然后有一轮下注，那么你
get the fourth card in public on the
在公共场合获得第四张牌
table they're spitting around then you
桌子他们随你吐痰
get the five fifth card on the table
拿到五张五张牌
there's a bending drop so there's a
有一个弯曲下降，所以有一个
total of four betting rounds and four
共有 四个 下注轮和四个
torrontés of information revelation if
信息披露的热门
you will the only the first tranche is
你会是唯一的第一档电量 为
private and they omits public from there
私人，他们 从那里省略了公众
and this is probably probably by far the
这可能是迄今为止的
most popular game in AI and just the
人工智能中最受欢迎的游戏
general public in terms of imperfect
一般 公众的不完善
information so it's probably the most
信息所以它可能是 最多的
popular spectator game to watch right so
观看流行的观众比赛
which is why it's a super exciting game
这就是为什么它是一个超级 刺激的游戏
tackle so it sits on the order of chess
因此它 处于国际象棋的顺序
I would say in terms of popularity in
我会说在人气方面
terms of AI setting it as the bar of
AI的条款将其设置为
what is intelligence
什么是情报
so in 2017 labret does how do you
所以在2017年， labret你是怎么做的
pronounce it Liberato lebra das lebra
发音为Liberato lebra das lebra
does beats little laughing they're a
不拍 小笑 他们是一个
little bit Latin LeBron is beat a few
拉丁勒布朗有点 打败 了一些
for expert human players can you
对于专业的人类玩家可以
describe that event what you learned
描述你所学到的事件
from it what was it like what was the
从它是什么 你喜欢什么 了
process in general for people who have
过程一般谁拥有 人
not read the papers and study yeah so
不读报纸 ， 研究是的
the event was that we invited four of
事件是我们邀请了四个
the top 10 players with these are
排名前10的 球员 都是
specialist players in heads-up no Limit
单挑 专家队员 无限制
Texas Hold'em which is very important
德州扑克非常重要
because this game is actually quite
因为这个游戏实际上相当
different than the the multiplayer
不同于多人游戏
version we brought me in to Pittsburgh
版本我们把我带到了匹兹堡
to play at the reverse casino
在反向赌场玩
for twenty days we wanted to get a
二十天 我们想得到一个
hundred and twenty thousand hands in
十二万手
because we wanted to get statistical
因为我们想得到统计数据
significance so it's a lot of hands for
意义所以它有很多动手
humans to play even for this top pros
人类甚至为 这位顶级职业选手打球
who play fairly quickly normally so we
谁能正常比赛， 所以我们
couldn't just have one of them play so
不能只是 他们中的 一个 打 这么
many hands twenty days they were playing
多手 20天他们被打
basically morning to evening and he
基本上是从早到晚和他
raised two hundred thousand as a little
一点点筹集了二 十万
incentive for them to play and the
激励 他们发挥和
setting was so that they didn't all get
设置是因为他们没有得到
fifty thousand we actually paid them out
我们实际上已经付出了五万
based on how they did against the AI
基于他们如何对抗AI
each so they had an incentive to play as
每个人都有动力 去玩
hard as they could whether they're way
尽管他们是这样的，他们还是 很难
ahead the way behind or right at the
在前面或后面的路上
mark of beating the AI and you don't
击败AI的标志， 你不
make any money unfortunately right no we
不幸的 是，不管我们是谁
can't make any money so so originally a
所以原来不能赚钱
couple of years earlier I actually
几年前我实际上
explored whether we could actually play
探讨我们是否真的可以玩
for money because that would be of
为了钱， 因为那将是
course interesting as well to play
当然也很有趣
against the top people for money but the
反对顶级人民的钱但是
Pennsylvania Gaming Board said no so so
宾夕法尼亚州博彩委员会说不是这样
if we couldn't so this is much like an
如果我们不能 这样，这就像一个
exhibit like for a musician or a boxer
表演喜欢音乐家或拳击手
or something like that
或类似的东西
nevertheless you're keeping track of the
尽管如此， 你仍在跟踪
money and brought us one close to two
钱 给我们带来了近两个
million dollars I think so so if there
百万美元我认为如此，如果 有的话
if it was for real money if you were
如果这是真钱 ，如果 你是
able to earn money that was a quite
能够 赚到相当的钱
impressive and inspiring achievement
令人印象深刻的鼓舞人心
just a few details what what were the
只是一些细节是什么
players looking at I mean were they
看着我的意思是他们的球员
behind the computer what was the
在电脑后面是 什么
interface like yes there they were
界面就像是他们在那里
playing much like they normally do these
像他们通常那样玩
top players when they play this game
当他们玩这个游戏的顶级玩家
they play mostly online so they used to
他们大多数都在网上玩， 所以他们习惯了
playing through what UI yes and they did
通过什么UI玩，他们做了
the same thing here so there was this
同样的事情 ， 所以有这个
layout you could imagine there's a table
布局你可以想象 有一张桌子
on the screen this the the human sitting
在屏幕上这是人类的坐姿
there and then there's the AI sitting
在那里然后是AI坐着
there and the the screen source
那里和屏幕来源
everything is happening the cards coming
一切 即将 发生 卡
out and so the bets being made and we
所以我们正在制造赌注
also had the betting history for the
还有投注历史
human so if the human for what what had
人类如果人类为了什么而拥有的东西
happened in the ham so far they could
到目前为止他们可以在火腿上发生
actually reference back
实际参考 回来
and and and so forth is there a reason
和等等是有原因的
they were given access to the betting
他们 可以获得 投注
history for well we just uh it's a it
好的历史我们就是这样吧
didn't really matter that they wouldn't
并不重要，他们不会
have forgotten anyway these are top
已经忘记了这些都是顶级的
quality people but we just want to put
优质的人，但我们只想放
out there so it's not a question for
在那里所以 这不是 一个问题
human for getting and the AI somehow
以某种方式获取和人工智能的人类
trying to get advantage of better memory
想获得 更好的内存的 优势
so what was that like I mean that was an
那是什么 意思， 我的 意思是，这 是一个
incredible accomplishment so what did it
令人难以置信的成就所以它做了什么
feel like before the event did you have
感觉就像你 之前的活动 一样
doubt hope
怀疑希望
where was your confidence at yeah that's
你对自己的信心在哪里
great so a great question so eighteen
非常棒的问题， 所以十八岁
months earlier I had organized the
几个月前我组织了
similar brains versus AI competition
类似的大脑与AI竞争
with our previous a I call clerical and
与我们 以前的 一个我打电话给神职人员和
we couldn't beat the humans so this time
这次我们无法击败人类
around it was only eighteen months later
周围只有 十 八个月后
and I knew that this new AI Lovato's was
我知道 这个新的AI Lovato是
way stronger but it's hard to say how
方式更强， 但很难说 如何
you'll do against the top humans before
你以前会对抗顶级人类
you try so I thought we had about a
你这么试试我认为我们有一个
50/50 shot and the international betting
50/50投篮和国际投注
sites put us a us as a four to one or
网站把我们 称为四对一或
five to one underdog so it's kind of
五到一个失败者，所以它是那种
interesting that people really believe
有趣的是 人们真的 相信
in people and I get over AI not just
在人和我 不仅仅是AI
people people don't just believe over
人们不仅仅相信
believing themselves but they have
相信自己，但他们有
overconfidence in other people as well
对其他人的过度自信也是如此
compared to the performance of AI and
相对于 AI 的 性能 和
yeah so we were afford to 105 to 108
是的，所以我们负担得起105到108
beating the humans in a row we were
我们连续击败了人类
still 50/50 on the international betting
国际博彩仍然是50/50
sites do you think there's something
网站你认为有什么东西
special and magical about poker and in
特殊而神奇的扑克 和
the way people think about it in a sense
在某种意义上人们 对它的 看法
you have I mean even in chess there's no
你的意思是即使在国际象棋中也没有
Hollywood movies poker is this the star
好莱坞电影扑克是这个明星
of many movies and there's this feeling
很多电影都有这种 感觉
that certain human facial expressions
某些人类的面部表情
and body language eye movement all these
和肢体语言眼睛运动所有这些
tells are critical to poker you can look
告诉对你可以看的扑克至关重要
into somebody's soul understand their
进入某人的灵魂了解他们的
betting strategy and so on there so
投注策略等等
that's probably why the possibly do you
那可能是你为什么这么做的原因
think that is why people have a
认为这就是人们拥有 的原因
confidence that humans will outperform
相信人类会跑赢大作
because AI systems cannot in
因为AI系统无法进入
construct perceive these kinds of tells
构造感知这些类型的讲述
they're only looking at betting patterns
他们只关注 投注模式
and and nothing else the betting
并且没有别的投注
patterns and and statistics so what's
什么是模式和统计数据
more important to you if you step back
如果你退一步对你更重要
and human players human versus human
人类与人类的人类
what's the role these tells of these
这些对这些的作用是什么
ideas that we romanticize yeah so I
我们浪漫化的想法是的，所以我
split it into two parts so one is why do
把它分成两部分 ，这就是 为什么呢
humans trust he much more than AI and
人类比AI和他更信任他
all have overconfidence in humans yes I
所有人都对人类过度自信 是的
think that's that's not really related
认为那不是真的 相关
to tell a question it's just that
告诉一个问题就是这样
they've seen these top players how good
他们看到这些顶级球员有多好
they are and they're really fantastic so
他们和他们真是太棒 所以
it's just hard to believe therefore that
它只是很难 说 ，因此相信
the Navy I could beat them yeah so I
海军我可以打败他们， 所以我
think that's where that comes from and
认为这 是来自和
and that's actually maybe a more general
而这实际上可能更为一般
lesson about the AI that until you've
关于人工智能的教训，直到你
seen it over perform a human it's hard
看到它执行人类很难
to believe it it could but then the
相信它可以，但那么
tails a lot of these top players they're
很多 这些顶级球员都是他们的尾巴
so good at hiding tails that among the
擅长隐藏其中的尾巴
top players it's actually not really
顶级球员 实际上并不是真的
worth it for them to invest a lot of
值得他们 投入 大量 资金
effort trying to find tails in each
试图找到每个尾巴的努力
other because there's a so good at
另外因为有在这么好
hiding them so yes at the kind of Friday
在周五那种时候隐藏他们
evening game tells are gonna be a huge
晚上的比赛告诉会是一个巨大的
thing you can read other people and if
你可以阅读其他人的 事情 ，如果
you're a good reader you you'll read
你是个好读者， 你会读到的
them like an open book but at the top
他们就像一本打开的书， 但在 顶部
levels of poker no details become a list
扑克水平没有细节成为一个列表
of the much much smaller and smaller
越来越小
aspect of the game as you go to the top
当你走到 顶端时 ，游戏的方面
levels the the amount of strategies the
调整策略的数量
amount of possible actions is is very
可能的行动量 是非常的
large ten to the power of one hundred
大 10到100的动力
plus so there has to be some I've read a
加上所以我必须读一些
few the papers related it has it has to
很少有与之相关的论文
form some abstractions of various hands
形成一些各种手的抽象
and actions so what kind of abstractions
和行动所以是什么样的抽象
are effective for the game of poker yeah
是有效的扑克游戏 呀
so you're exactly right so when you go
所以，当你离开时 ，你是完全正确的
from a game tree that's ten to the 161
从一个十到161的游戏树
especially in an imperfect information
特别是在不完善的信息中
game it's way too large to solve
游戏太大而无法解决
directly even with our fastest ik
直接与我们最快的ik
finding algorithms so you wanna abstract
寻找算法让你想抽象
it first and abstraction in games is
它首先和 游戏中的 抽象 是
much trickier than abstraction in mdps
比 mdps中的 抽象更棘手
or other single agent settings because
或其他单个代理设置，因为
you have these abstraction pathologies
你有这些抽象的病态
that if I have a finer grained
如果我有一个更精细的粒度
abstraction the strategy that I can get
抽象我可以得到的策略
from that for the real game might
从 那个 真正的游戏可能
actually be worse than the strategy I
实际上比我的策略更糟糕
can get from the coarse-grained
可以从粗粒度中获得
abstraction if you have to be very
抽象， 如果你必须非常
careful now the the kinds of
现在小心的那种
abstractions just to zoom out we're
抽象只是为了缩小我们
talking about there's the hands
谈论有手
abstractions and then there's betting
抽象，然后有赌博
strategies yeah what I think actions
策略是的，我认为行动
yeah baiting access or so there's
是的诱饵 访问 或所以有
information obstruction to talk about
信息障碍谈谈
general games information abstraction
一般游戏信息 抽象
which is the abstraction of what chance
这是什么机会的抽象
does and this would be the cards in the
是的，这将是在卡片中
case of poker and then there's action
扑克的情况， 然后有行动
abstraction which is abstracting the
抽象的抽象
actions of the actual players which
实际玩家的行动
would be bits in the case of poker
在扑克的情况下会是比特
yourself and the other players yes
你自己和其他球员是的
yourself and other players and for
你自己和其他球员
information abstraction we were
信息抽象我们是
completely automated so these were these
完全自动化所以 这些 都是这些
are algorithms but they do what we call
是算法， 但 他们做我们 所说的
potential aware abstraction where we
潜在的意识抽象我们在哪里
don't just look at the value of the hand
不只是 看手的价值
but also how it might materialize in the
但它 也可能 如何 实现
good or bad hands over time and it's a
随着时间的推移 好坏 ，这是一个
certain kind of bottom-up process with
某一种 自下而上的过程
integer programming there and clustering
那里的整数编程和聚类
and various aspects how do you build
和各方面你如何 建立
build this abstraction and then in the
构建这个抽象，然后在
action abstraction there it's largely
行动抽象在那里很大程度上
based on how humans other and other AIS
基于人类如何和其他AIS
have played this game in the past but in
曾经玩过这个游戏，但在过去
the beginning we actually use an
一开始 我们 实际使用了
automated action abstraction technology
自动化动作抽象技术
which is provably convergent that it
它可以证明是收敛的
finds the optimal combination of eight
找到八个的最佳组合
sizes but it's not very scalable so we
尺寸， 但它不是很可扩展，所以我们
couldn't use it for the whole game but
不能使用 它整场比赛 ，但
we used it for the first couple of
我们把它用于 前几
betting actions so what's more important
投注行动所以更重要的是
the strength of the hand so the
这样的手 的 力量
information retraction or the how you
信息收回或 你 如何
play them the actions does
扮演他们的行动
you know the romanticized notion again
你又知道了浪漫主义的观念
is that it doesn't matter what hands you
是什么交给 你 并不 重要
have that the actions the betting may be
有投注 可能 的行动
the way you win no matter what hands you
你无论用什么手都赢了
have yeah so that's why you have to play
有， 所以这就是你必须玩的原因
a lot of hands so that the role of luck
很多手让 运气 的作用
gets smaller so you could otherwise get
变小， 这样你就可以得到
lucky and get some good hands and then
幸运的是，然后得到一些好手
you're gonna win the match even with
你 甚至 会赢得这场比赛
thousands of hands you can get lucky
成千上万的手 你可以幸运
because there's so much variance in No
因为No的差异太大了
Limit Texas Hold'em because if we both
限制德州扑克， 因为如果我们两个
go all-in it's a huge stack or variant
全押 它是一个巨大的堆栈或变体
so there are these massive swings in No
所以在No。中有这些大规模的波动
Limit Texas Hold'em so that's why you
限制德州扑克，这就是你的原因
have to play not just thousands but over
要发挥不 只是几千但在
a hundred thousand hands don't get
十万只手不能得到
statistical significance let me ask
统计意义让我问一下
another way this question if you didn't
另一种方式，如果你没有这个问题
even look at your hands but they didn't
甚至看着你的手，但他们没有
know that the your opponents didn't know
知道你的 对手不知道
that how well would you be able to do oh
那你能做 得多好哦
that's a good question there's actually
实际上这是一个很好的问题
I heard this story that this is
我听到这个故事， 这是
Norwegian female poker player goal and
挪威女扑克玩家的目标和
at uber stud who's actually won a
在uber stud谁真的赢了
tournament by doing exactly that but
通过做 那个比赛但是
that would be extremely rare so so I
那是 非常罕见的 ，所以我
cannot really play well the hands do
手不能真正发挥好
have some role to play oh yes so LeBron
有一些角色可以玩哦是的 所以勒布朗
is does not use as far as I understand a
据 我所知， 是 不是用 的
used learning methods deep learning is
用过的学习方法深度学习是
there room for learning in you know
你知道有学习的空间
there's no reason why lab artist doesn't
实验室 艺术家没有理由不这样做
you know combined with an alphago type
你知道结合alphago类型
approach for estimating the quality for
评估质量的方法
function estimator what are your
功能估算器你的是什么
thoughts on this maybe as compared to
对此的想法可能与之相比
another algorithm which I'm not that
另一种我不是那种算法
familiar with deep stack the the engine
熟悉深层堆叠引擎
that does use deep learning that it's
这确实使用深度学习，它的
unclear how well it does but
目前尚不清楚它的表现如何
nevertheless uses deep learning so what
然而，使用深度学习是什么
are your thoughts about learning methods
你对学习方法的看法
to aid in the way that teller Broadus
协助出纳员Broadus的方式
plays the game of poker yeah so as you
扮演 扑克游戏 是的，就像你一样
said Lee barratto's did not use learning
说李巴拉托没有使用学习
methods and played very well without
方法并 没有很好地 发挥
them since then we have actually
他们从那以后我们实际上
actually here we have a couple of papers
实际上我们有 几篇论文
on things that do use learning technique
关于使用 学习技巧的 事情
Saxon so and deep learning in particular
撒克逊所以和深学习特别
and the sort of the way you're talking
以及你说话的那种方式
about where it's learning an evaluation
关于 它在哪里学习评估
function but in imperfect information
功能但信息不完善
games unlike let's say in Co or now now
不像我们在Co 或现在说的游戏
also in chess and shogi it's not some
国际象棋和棋子也不是一些
sufficient to learn an evaluation for a
足以学习评估
state because the value of an
因为一个州的价值
information set depends not only on the
信息集不仅取决于
exact state but it also depends on both
确切的状态，但它也取决于 两者
players beliefs like if I have a bad
球员的信念，如果我有一个坏人
hand I'm much better off if the opponent
如果对手， 我会好多了
thinks I'm have a good hand and vice
我认为我有一手好坏
versa if I have a good hand I'm much
反之亦然，如果我有一手好牌， 我会很多
better off if the opponent believes I
如果对手相信我会更好
have a bad hand so the value of a state
有一个坏手所以一个国家的价值
is not just a function of the cards it
它不仅仅是 卡片 的功能
depends on if you will the path of play
取决于你是否会参加比赛
but only to the extent that is captured
但只是在捕获的范围内
in the belief distributions so so that's
在信仰分布中所以这样
why it's not as simple as as it is
为什么它不像它那么简单
imperfect information games another one
不完美的信息游戏另一个
I'd say it's simple there either it's of
我会说这很简单
course very complicated computationally
当然计算非常复杂
there too but at least conceptually it's
那里也是，但 至少 在 概念上是这样的
very straightforward there's a state
非常直截了当的是一个州
there's an evaluation function you can
你可以使用评估功能
try to learn it here you have to do
尝试在这里学习它你必须做
something more and what we do is in one
更多的东西，我们做的是 一个
of these papers we're looking at
我们正在研究这些论文
allowing where we allow with the
允许我们允许的地方
opponent to actually take different
对手实际上采取不同的
strategies at the leaf of the search
搜索 叶子的策略
tree as F if you will and and that is a
如果你 愿意，树就像F一样
different way of doing it and it doesn't
这样 做的 方式不同而且没有
assume therefore a particular way that
因此， 假设 一种特殊的方式
the opponent plays but it allows
对手比赛但是允许
opponent to choose from a set of
对手可以选择一套
different continuation strategies and
不同的延续策略和
that forces us to not be too optimistic
这迫使我们 不要 过于乐观
in our local head search and that's
在我们 当地的头部搜索，那是
that's one way you can do sound look
这是你可以做声音的一种方式
ahead search in imperfect information
提前搜索不完善的信息
games which is very different difficult
难度很大的游戏
and in us you were asking about deep
在 我们这里，你问得很深
stack what they did it was very
堆叠他们做了什么非常
different than what we do either in Lee
不同于我们在Lee做的事情
brothers or in this new work
兄弟或在这项新工作
they were gender and Umrah generating
他们是性别和副朝生成
various situations in the game then they
他们在游戏中的各种情况
were doing Luca head from there to the
正在做 卢卡头 从那里到
end of the game as if that was a start
比赛结束，好像那是一个开始
of a different game and then they were
他们是 一个不同的游戏
using deep learning to learn those
用深度学习来学习那些
values of those states but the states
这些州的价值， 但国家
were not just the physical states they
不只是身体状态 ，他们
include the belief distributions when
包括信仰分布时
you talk about look ahead for deep stack
你谈到了深筹码的前瞻性
or with libertas does it mean
或者与 libertas一起 意味着什么
considering every possibility that the
考虑到每一种可能性
game can involve is that we're talking
游戏可能 涉及 到 我们正在谈论
about extremely sort of like this
关于这种非常类似的事情
exponentially growth of a tree yes so
树的指数增长 是的
we're talking about exactly that
我们正在谈论的确如此
much like you do in Alpha Beta search or
就像你在Alpha Beta搜索中所做的那样
want to crawl to research but with
要爬网研究 但
different techniques so there's a
不同的技术 所以有一个
different search algorithm and then we
不同的搜索算法然后我们
have to deal with the leaves differently
必须以不同的方式处理树叶
so if you think about what Lee brothers
所以，如果你想想 李兄弟
did we didn't have to worry about this
我们没有必要担心这个
because we only did it at the end of the
因为我们只在 最后 做到 了
game so we would always terminate into a
游戏所以我们总是会终止成一个
real situation and we would know what to
真实的情况，我们会知道该怎么 做
payout this it didn't do this
支付这个 它没有这样做
depth limited loka heads but now in this
深度限制洛卡头， 但现在在这
new paper which is called depth limited
被 称为深度限制的新论文
I think it's called depth limited
我认为它被称为深度限制
research for imperfect information games
对不完全信息游戏的研究
we can actually do sound depth limited
我们实际上可以做声音深度有限
look at it so we can actually started
看看 它， 这样我们才能真正开始
with a look ahead
展望未来
from the beginning of the game on
从比赛开始
because that's too complicated to do for
因为那太复杂了
this whole long game
整整一场比赛
so in Lee brothers we were just doing it
因此，在李氏兄弟，我们只是做
for the end so and then the other side
为了结束所以然后 另一边
this belief distribution so is it
这种信念分布也是如此
explicitly modeled what kind of beliefs
明确地模仿了什么样的信仰
that the opponent might have yeah yeah
对手可能有，是的， 是的
it is explicitly modeled but it's not
它是明确建模的，但事实并非如此
assumed the beliefs are actually output
假设信念实际上是输出的
not input of course the starting beliefs
当然不输入起始信念
are input but they just fall from the
输入，但他们只是从下跌
rules of the game because we know that
游戏规则， 因为我们知道
the dealer deals uniformly from the dick
经销商统一来自迪克
so I know that every pair of cards that
所以我知道那双卡
you might have is equally likely I know
你可能有同样可能我知道
that for a fact
事实上
that's as follows from the rules of the
这是 从规则的 如下
game of course except the two cards that
当然 ， 除了游戏的两张牌 是
I have I know you don't have those yes
我知道你没有 那些是的
you have to take that into account
你必须考虑 到这一点
that's called card removal and that's
这就是所谓的卡片移除
very important is the dealing always
非常重要的是处理总是
coming from a single deck in the heads
来自头部的单层甲板
up so you can assume single deck know
所以你可以假设单层甲板知道
that if some if if I have the ace of
如果有的话， 如果我有王牌的话
spades I know you don't have an ace of
黑桃我知道你没有王牌
spades
黑桃
okay so in the beginning your belief is
好的，所以一 开始你的信念就是
basically the fact that it's a fair
基本上这是一个公平的事实
dealing of hands but how do you adjust
处理手但你如何调整
start to adjust that belief well that's
开始 很好 地调整 那个信念
a where this beauty of games here it
这里的游戏之美吧
comes so nash equilibrium which john
来自约翰的 纳什均衡
nash introduced in 1950 introduces what
纳什在1950年介绍了什么
rational play is when you have more than
理性的游戏就是当你拥有更多
one player and these are pairs of
一个玩家，这些是成对的
strategies where strategies are
战略的战略
contingency plans one for each player so
应急计划为每个球员一个
neither player wants to
无论玩家想要
deviate to a different strategy given
偏向于 给出 不同的策略
that the other doesn't deviate but as a
另一个 并没有偏离，而是作为一个
side effect you get the beliefs from
副作用你得到 了信仰
Bayes rule so Nash equilibrium really
贝叶斯 确实如此纳什均衡
isn't just deriving in these imperfect
不只是衍生出这些不完美的东西
information games Nash equilibrium
信息游戏纳什均衡
doesn't just define strategies it also
不只是定义的策略也
defines beliefs for both us and it
定义了我们和它的信念
defines beliefs for each state so at the
定义信念对于每个状态，从而在
each state it's if they take all
每个状态是 ，如果他们采取一切
information sets at each information set
每个信息集的信息集
in the game there's a set of different
在游戏中有一套不同的
states that we might be in but I don't
说我们可能在，但我没有
know which one we're in Nash equilibrium
知道哪一个我们处于纳什均衡状态
tells me exactly what is a probability
告诉我到底是什么概率
distribution over those real world
分布在那些现实世界中
states in my mind how does naturally
在我的脑海中陈述 自然是 怎样的
give you that distribution so why I'll
给你那个分配，为什么我会
do a simple example so you know the game
做一个简单的例子让你 知道游戏
rock-paper-scissors so we can draw it as
摇滚纸剪刀， 所以我们可以画它
player 1 moves first and then player 2
玩家1首先移动然后移动玩家2
moves but of course it's important that
移动但当然重要的是
player 2 doesn't know what player 1
玩家2不知道玩家1是什么
moved otherwise player 2 would win every
移动否则球员2.将打好每
time so we can draw that as an
时间， 所以我们可以把 它 画 成一个
information set where player 1 makes one
玩家1制作的信息集
of three moves first and then there's an
首先是三个动作，然后是一个
information set for player 2 so player 2
为玩家2设置的信息，因此玩家2
doesn't know which of those nodes the
不知道那些节点中的哪一个
world is it but once we know the
世界是它，但一旦我们知道了
strategy for player 1 Nash equilibrium
球员1纳什均衡的策略
will say that you play 1/3 Rock 1/3
会说你玩1/3 Rock 1/3
paper 1/3 caesars from that I can derive
纸张1/3 凯撒，我可以得出
my beliefs of the information set that
我对信息集的看法
they wanted 1/3 wants it though so Bayes
他们希望1/3想要贝叶斯
gives you that basis you but is that
给你那个基础但是就是这样
specific to a particular player or is it
特定于特定玩家或是它
is there something you quickly update
有什么东西你快速更新
with the game theory isn't really player
与博弈论并不是真正的玩家
specific so that's what also why we
特定的，这也是我们为什么的原因
don't need any data we don't need any
不需要任何我们不需要的数据
history how these particular humans
历史如何这些特殊的人类
played in the past or how any AI or even
在过去玩或如何任何AI甚至
had played before it's all about
在玩之前已经玩过了
rationality so we just think the AI just
合理性所以我们只是认为 人工智能
thinks about what would a rational
思考一个理性的东西
opponent do and what would I do if I
对手， 如果我，我该怎么做
were right I am rational and that that's
是对的我是理性的那就是
that's the idea of game theory so it's
这就是博弈论的概念所以它就是这样
really a data free opponent free
真正的数据免费对手免费
approach sir comes from the design of
做法先生来自设计
the game as opposed to the design of the
相对于的设计游戏
player exactly if there's no opponent
如果没有对手，确切地说球员
modeling per se I mean we've done some
建模本身我的意思是我们做了 一些
work on combining opponent modeling with
将对手建模与...结合起来的工作
game theory so you couldn't exploit weak
博弈论让你无法利用弱势
players even more but that's another
球员更多，但那是另一个
strand and in the Lee brothers we didn't
我和Lee兄弟没有
turn that on because I decided that
转过来因为我决定了
these players are too good and when you
这些球员太好了，当你
start to exploit an opponent you'll
开始利用你的对手
typically open yourself up self up to
通常打开 自己
exploitation and these guys have so few
剥削和这些家伙很少
holes to exploit and they're world's
洞穴利用， 他们是世界的
leading experts in counter exploitation
领先的反剥削专家
so I decided that we're not gonna turn
所以我决定我们 不会转
that stuff on actually I saw a few
事实上，我看到了一些东西
papers exploiting opponents it sound
论文利用对手的 声音
very interesting to explore do you think
你觉得探索很有意思
there's room for exploitation generally
一般来说都有剥削的空间
outside of LeBron us is is there subject
在勒布朗之外，我们就是 主题
or people differences that could be
或者人与人之间的差异
exploited maybe not just in poker but in
被剥削的可能不只是 在扑克中， 而是在
general interactions negotiations all
一般互动谈判全部
these other domains that yours
您的其他域名
considering yeah I definitely we've done
考虑是的，我绝对做到了
some work on that and I really like
一些工作，我真的很 喜欢
their work at hybridize is the two so
他们在 杂交的工作就是这 两个
you figure out what would a rational
你弄明白什么 是 理性的
opponent do and by the way that's safe
对手这样做， 顺便说一下这是安全的
in these zero-sum games two player
在这些零和游戏中两名球员
zero-sum games because if the opponent
零和游戏，因为如果对手
does something irrational yes it might
做不合理的事是的
show throw off my beliefs but the amount
显示抛弃我的 信仰，但 金额
that the player can gain by throwing off
玩家可以通过甩掉获得
my belief is always less than they lose
我的信念总是少于失败
by playing poorly so so it's safe but
通过打得不好这样安全但是
still if somebody's weak as a player you
如果有人作为一名球员的弱点， 你还是会
might want to play differently to
可能想要以不同的方式玩
exploit them more so that you can think
更多地利用它们以便你能够思考
about it this way a game theoretic
关于它 这样 一个游戏理论
strategies are unbeatable but it doesn't
战略是无与伦比的， 但事实并非如此
maximally beat the other opponent so the
最大限度地击败对方所以
winnings per hand might be better with a
每手牌的奖金可能会更好
different strategy and the hybrid is
不同的策略和混合 是
that you start from a game theoretic
你从游戏理论开始
approach and then as you gain data from
接近然后从中获取数据
about the opponent in certain parts of
关于某些部分的对手
the game tree that in those parts of the
在那些部分 的 游戏树
game tree you start to tweak your
游戏树你开始调整 你的
strategy more and more towards
战略越来越倾向于
exploitation while still staying fairly
剥削， 但仍保持公平
close to the game theoretic strategy so
接近游戏 理论策略所以
as to not open yourself up to
至于不打开自己
exploitation too much
剥削太多了
how do you do that do you try to vary up
你是怎么做到这一点的， 你 试图 改变
strategies make it unpredictable it's
策略让它变得不可预测
like what is it
喜欢它是什么
tit-for-tat strategies in prisoner's
囚犯的 针锋相对 策略
dilemma or well it doesn't that that's a
困境或者 它不是 那个
repeated game kind of prisoner's dilemma
重复的游戏类型的 囚徒困境
repeats it games but but even there
重复 它的游戏，但即使在那里
there's no proof that says that that's
没有证据表明 那是那样的
the best thing but experimentally it
最好的东西，但 实验它
actually does does does well so what
实际上确实做得很好
kind of games are there first of all I
首先是我的游戏类型
don't know if this is something that you
不知道这是不是你的意思
could just summarize there's perfect
可以总结出那里的完美
information games or all the
信息游戏或所有
informations on the table there is
桌子上有信息
imperfect information games there's
有不完善的信息游戏
repeated games you play over and over
你一遍 又一遍地重复比赛
there's zero-sum games there's
那里有零和游戏
nonzero-sum games yeah and then there's
非零和游戏耶 ，然后有
a really important distinction you're
你是一个非常重要的区别
making two-player versus more players so
让两名球员与更多的球员 ，所以
what are what other games out there and
什么是其他游戏和那里
what's the difference for example with
例如，有什么区别
this two-player game versus more players
这个双人游戏与更多玩家相比
yeah what are the key differences right
是的是什么权利的关键差异
here so let me start from the the basic
这里让 我 从基础开始 吧
so a repeated game is a game where the
所以重复的游戏是一个游戏
same exact game is played over and over
同样精确的游戏一遍又一遍地播放
in these extensive form games where
在这些广泛的形式游戏 中
think about three form maybe with these
想想三者形成 可能与这些
information says to represent incomplete
信息表示代表不完整
information you can have kind of
您可以拥有的信息
repetitive interactions even repeated
重复的互动甚至重复
games are a special case of that by the
游戏是一个特例
way but if the game doesn't have to be
的方式，但如果游戏没有被
exactly the same selectively sourcing
完全相同的 选择性 采购
all trips yes we kind of see it the same
所有旅行是的我们有点看到它
supply base year to year but what I'm
每年的供应基数，但我是什么
buying is a little different every time
买的是有点不同， 每次
and the supply base is a little
和供给基是一个 小
different every time and so on so it's
不同的每次等等 所以它的
not really repeated so to find a purely
不是真的重复这样才能找到一个纯粹的
repeated game is actually very rare in
重复博弈 实际上是非常罕见的
the world so they're really a very
世界所以 他们真的非常
coarse model of what's going on then if
然后，如果发生了什么的粗略模型
you move up from repeat just repeated
你从 重复刚刚重复 上来
simple repeated matrix games not all the
简单的重复矩阵游戏 不是全部
way to extensive form games but in
广泛的形式游戏的方式，但在
between
之间
they're stochastic games where you know
他们是你知道的随机游戏
this these think about it like these
这些就像这些一样思考
little matrix games
小矩阵游戏
and when you take an action and your
当你采取行动和你的
home takes an action they determine not
家庭采取他们不确定的行动
which next state I'm going to next game
下一个状态，我将下一场比赛
I'm going to but the distribution over
我要去分发 了
next games where I might be going to so
下一场比赛，我可能 会这样做
so that's the stochastic game but it's
这是随机游戏，但它是
like matrix games repeated stochastic
像矩阵游戏一样重复随机
games extensive form games that is from
游戏广泛形式的游戏来自
less to more general and and poker is an
少到一般，扑克是一个
example of the last one so it's really
最后一个的例子，所以它真的
the most general setting extensive form
最一般的设置广泛的形式
games and that's kind of what the AI
游戏， 这就是人工智能
community has been working on and being
社区一直在努力和存在
benched marked on with this heads-up No
这个单挑号码上标有标记
Limit Texas Hold'em
限制德州扑克
can you describe extensive form games
你能描述一下大型游戏吗？
what was the motto here yeah so if you
这里的座右铭是什么，如果你
imagine with the tree form so it's
用树形来想象 它是如此
really the tree form like in chess
真的像国际象棋一样的树形态
there's a search tree versus a matrix is
搜索树与矩阵相比
a matrix yeah and that's the new matrix
矩阵耶，那是新的 矩阵
is called the matrix form or by matrix
被称为矩阵形式或 矩阵
form or normal form game and here you
形式或正常形式的游戏，在这里
have the tree form so you can actually
有树形式，所以你可以
do certain types of reasoning there that
那里做某些类型的推理
you'll lose the information when you go
你去 的 时候 会丢失 信息
to normal form there's a certain form of
正常形式 有某种形式
equivalence like if you go from three
等同，如果你从三岁开始
form and you say it every possible
形式，你说每一个可能的
contingency plan is the strategy then I
应急计划是我的策略
can actually go back to the normal form
实际上可以 恢复正常 形式
but I lose some information from the
但 我失去了一些信息
lack of sequentiality then the
缺乏顺序性然后
multiplayer versus two-player
多人对阵双人
distinction is an important one
区别是重要的
so two-player games in zero-sum are
所以零和的双人游戏是
conceptually easier and computationally
在概念上更容易和计算
easier there's still huge like this one
更容易仍然像这一样巨大
this one but they're conceptually easier
这个，但它们在概念上更容易
and computationally easier in that
并且计算上更容易
conceptually you don't have to worry
从概念上讲， 你 不必担心
about which equilibrium is the other guy
关于哪个均衡是另一个人
going to play when there are multiple
有多个时去玩
because any equilibrium strategy is a
因为任何均衡策略都是一个
best response to any other equilibrium
对任何其他均衡的最佳反应
strategy so I can play a different
战略所以我可以发挥不同
equilibrium from you and we'll still get
来自你的平衡，我们仍然会得到
the right values of the game that falls
正确的游戏价值
apart even with two players when you
当你还有两名球员时
have general some games even without
甚至没有一般游戏
cooperation just even without
甚至没有合作
cooperation so there's a big gap from
合作所以有一个很大的差距
two player zero-sum to two-player
两名球员零和 两名球员
general sum or even to three player
一般总和甚至 三个球员
zero-sum that's that's a big gap
零和那是一个很大的差距
at least in theory can you maybe not
至少在理论上你可能没有
mathematically provide the intuition why
在数学上提供了直觉的原因
it all falls apart with three or more
一切都因三个或更多而分崩离析
players it seems like you should still
球员似乎你应该仍然
be able to have a Nash equilibrium that
能够 达到纳什均衡
yeah that's instructive that holds okay
是的，这是有益的，保持 不错
so it is true that all finite games have
所以 有限的游戏 都是如此
a Nash equilibrium so this is what your
纳什均衡 所以这就是你的
Nash actually proved so they do have a
纳什实际证明他们确实有一个
Nash equilibrium that's not a problem
纳什均衡，这 不是一个 问题
the problem is that there can be many
问题是 可能有 很多
and then there's a question of which
然后有一个问题
equilibrium to select so and if you
平衡选择如此，如果你
select your strategy from a different
从 不同的角度 选择你的策略
equilibrium and I select mind then did
平衡，我选择心灵 然后做
what does that mean I and in this non
这是什么意思 我和 这个非
zero sum games we may lose some joint
零和游戏我们可能会失去 一些联合
benefits we hope by being just simply
我们希望通过简单的方式获益
stupid we could actually both be better
愚蠢我们实际上可能都会更好
off if we did something else yes and in
关 如果我们这样做别的 东西 是和
three player you get other problems also
三个球员你也得到其他问题
like collusion that maybe you and I can
就像 你和我可以 勾结一样
get up on a third player and we can do
起床第三个球员，我们可以做到
radically better by colluding so that
从根本上通过勾结 这样 效果 会 更好
there are lots of issues that come up
有很多问题出现了
there
那里
so no Brown student you workers on this
所以没有 布朗的学生就是这样的工人
has mentioned I looked through the AMA
已经提到过我看过 AMA
and read it he mentioned that the
并读 了他提到的那个
ability of poker players to collaborate
扑克玩家 的合作能力
will make the game he was asked the
会让他被问到这个游戏
question of how would you make the game
你将 如何 制作 游戏的问题
of poker or both of you were asked the
扑克或 你们两个被问到了
question how would you make the game of
问你将如何 制作游戏
poker
扑克
beyond being solvable by current AI
超出当前AI可解决的范围
methods and he said that there's not
方法，他说，没有
many ways of making poker more difficult
许多让扑克更难的方法
but collaboration or cooperation between
但是 之间的 合作 或合作
players would make it extremely
球员会非常努力
difficult so can you provide the
很难， 所以你能提供
intuition behind why that is if you
直觉背后为什么如果你
agree with that idea yeah so we've done
有 这种想法呀 ，所以我们所做的同意
a lot of work coalitional games and we
很多工作联盟游戏 和我们
actually have a paper here with my other
实际上 我的另 一篇文章 在这里
student cappella Farina and some other
学生 无伴娘法里纳 和其他一些
collaborators on after net nips on that
合作者在网上扼杀了之后
actually just came back from the poster
实际上刚刚从海报上 回来 了
session where we present life so when
我们在什么时候呈现生活的会议
you have a collusion it's a it's a
你有一个勾结它是一个
different problem yes and it typically
不同的问题是，它通常
gets even harder then
然后变得更难
even the game representations some of
甚至是游戏中的表现形式
the game representations don't really
游戏表示并不是真的
allow go to computation so we actually
允许去 计算，所以我们实际上
introduced a new game representation for
推出了新的游戏代表
for that is that kind of cooperation
因为那种 合作
part of the model is are you do you have
模特的一部分是你有你
do you have information about the fact
你有 关于这个事实的 信息吗？
that other players are cooperating or is
其他球员正在合作或是
it just this chaos that where nothing is
它 只是这个混乱的是，其中没有什么是
known so there's some something's
知道所以有一些东西
unknown can you give an example of a
不知道你能给出一个例子
collusion type game or Z you select
你选择的共谋式游戏或Z.
breach that so think about bridge it's
如此思考的错误就是它的 桥梁
like when you and I are on a team
就像你和我 在团队中一样
our payoffs are the same the problem is
我们的回报与问题相同
that we can't talk so so when I get my
当我得到我的时候，我们不能这么说
cards I can't whisper to you what my
卡我不能低声对你说什么
cards are that would not be allowed so
卡是不允许的
we have to somehow coordinate our
我们必须以某种方式协调我们的
strategies ahead of time and only ahead
战略提前，只有提前
of time and then there are certain
的时间，然后有 一定的
signals we can talk about but they have
我们可以谈论的信号，但他们有
to be such that the other team also
这样的另一个团队也是如此
understands them so so that that's
理解它们就是这样
that's an example where the coordination
这是协调的一个例子
is already built into the rules of the
已经内置 于规则中
game but in many other situations like
游戏， 但在许多 其他情况下， 如
auctions or negotiations or diplomatic
拍卖，谈判或外交
relationships poker it's not really
关系扑克它不是真的
built-in but it still can be very
内置的，但它仍然是 非常
helpful for the coders I've read you
对我读过你的程序员很有帮助
right somewhere the negotiations you
正确 的地方，你的谈判
come to the table with prior like a
像 以前 一样 来到桌子前面
strategy that like that you're willing
像 你愿意 那样的策略
to do and not willing to do those kinds
做，不愿意做那些
of things so how do you start to now
那么你怎么开始 呢
moving away from poker movie beyond
远离扑克电影
poker into other applications like
扑克成 其他应用程序
negotiations how do you start applying
谈判你如何开始申请
this to other and to other domains
这对其他域和其他域
yeah even real world domains that you've
是的，甚至是现实世界的域名
worked on yeah I actually have two
工作是的，我实际上有两个
start-up companies doing exactly that
创业公司正是 这样 做的
one is called strategic machine and
一个被称为战略机器和
that's for kind of build applications
这是一种构建应用程序
gaming sports all sorts of things like
游戏体育各种各样的事情
that any applications of this to
任何此类应用程序
business and to sports and to gaming to
商业， 体育和 游戏
various types of things for in finance
金融中的各种事物
electricity markets and so on and the
电力市场等等
other is called strategy robot where we
其他被称为 战略机器人我们
are taking this to military secure
正在把 这个带到 军事 安全
the cyber security and intelligence
网络安全和情报
applications I think you worked a little
申请我认为 你工作了一点
bit in how he put it advertisement sort
他怎么把广告排序
of suggesting ad kind of thing yeah
提出广告 的事情是的
auction that's another component
拍卖是另一个组成部分
optimized markets optimized but that's
优化的市场 优化，但那
much more about a combinatorial market
关于组合市场的更多信息
and optimization based technology that's
和基于优化的技术
not using these game theoretic reasoning
不使用这些博弈理论推理
technologies I think okay so what sort
技术我想好 了，什么 样的
of high level do you think about our
高级别 你认为我们的
ability to use game theoretic concepts
能够使用游戏理论概念
to model human behavior do you think do
你认为做人类行为的模型
you think human behavior is amenable to
你认为人类的 行为是可以接受的
this kind of modeling so outside of the
这种建模如此之外
poker games and where have you seen it
扑克游戏，你在哪里看到它
done successfully in your work I'm not
在你的工作中成功完成我不是
sure the goal really is modeling humans
确定目标确实是为人类建模
like for example if I'm playing a
例如， 如果我正在玩一个
zero-sum game yes I don't really care
零和游戏是的我 真的不在乎
that the opponent is actually following
对手实际上是跟随
my model of rational behavior because if
我的理性行为模型，因为如果
they're not that's even better for me
他们对我来说 并不是那么 好
right so so they see with the opponents
这样他们就能看到对手
and games there's a the prerequisite is
和游戏有一个先决条件是
that you've formalized the interaction
你已经 正式化了这种互动
in some way that can be amenable to
以某种方式可以服从
analysis and you've done this amazing
分析， 你做了 这个惊人的
work with mechanism design designing
与机械设计设计合作
games that have certain outcomes but so
具有某些结果的游戏， 但也是如此
I'll tell you an example for my for my
我会告诉你一个 我 的 例子
world of autonomous vehicles right we're
自主车的世界第一 右 我们
studying pedestrians and pedestrians and
研究行人和行人
cars negotiating this nonverbal
谈判这种非语言的汽车
communication there's this weird and
沟通有这种奇怪和
game dance of tension where pedestrians
行人紧张的游戏舞蹈
are basically saying I trusted you won't
基本上是说我相信你不会
kill me and so as a jaywalker I will
杀了我，所以作为一个jaywalker， 我会
step onto the road even though I'm
即使我是这样，走上这条路
breaking the law and there's this
违反法律就是这样
tension and the question is we really
紧张和问题是我们真的
don't know how to model that well in
不知道如何很好地建模
trying to model intent and so people
试图模仿意图等人
sometimes bring up ideas of game theory
有时提出博弈论的想法
and so on do you think that aspect of
等等 你认为那个方面
human behavior can use these kinds of
人类的行为可以使用 这些
imperfect information approaches
不完善的信息方法
modeling
造型
how do we how do you start to attack a
我们怎么开始攻击你
problem like that when you don't even
这样的问题，当你甚至不
know how the game design the game to
知道 游戏 如何 设计游戏
describe the situation in order to solve
描述情况以便解决
it okay so I haven't really thought
没关系所以我没想到
about jaywalking but one thing that I
关于jaywalking但我有一件事
think could be a good application in an
认为 可能 是一个很好的应用程序
autonomous vehicles is the following so
自动驾驶汽车如下
let's say that you have fleets of
让我们说你有舰队
autonomous cars operated by different
不同的自动驾驶汽车
companies so maybe here's the way more
公司也许这里的方式更多
fleet and here's the uber fleet if you
舰队， 如果你 ，这里是超级舰队
think about the rules of the road they
想想 他们的道路 规则
define certain little rules but that
定义一些小规则，但那
still leaves a huge strategy space open
仍然留下了巨大的战略空间
like as a simple example when cars merge
就像汽车合并时的一个简单例子
you know how he must merge you know they
你知道他必须合并你知道他们
slow down and look at each other and try
放慢速度，互相看看，试试吧
to I try to merge wouldn't it be better
我尝试合并不会更好
if these situations would all repeat
如果这些情况 都会重演
pre-negotiated so we can actually merge
经过预先协商，我们 实际上 可以 合并
at full speed and we know that this is
全速，我们知道 这 是
the situation this is how we do it and
这种情况是我们如何做到 这一点，
it's all gonna be faster but there are
它会更快，但有
way too many situations to negotiate
谈判的方式太多了
manually so you could do use automated
手动，所以你可以使用自动化
negotiation this is the idea at least
谈判是 这样 的想法，至少
you could use automated negotiation to
你可以使用自动协商
negotiate all of these situations or
谈判所有这些情况 或
many of them in advance and of course it
他们中的许多人提前 ，当然
might be that hey maybe you're not gonna
可能是嘿，也许你不会
always let me go first
总是让我先走
maybe you said okay well in these
也许你说这些好吧
situations all let you go first but in
情况都让你先走 ，但在
exchange you're gonna give me - how much
交换你会给我 - 多少钱
you're gonna let me go first in this
你会让我 先走 这 条路
situation yes
情况是的
so it's this huge combinatorial
所以这是一个巨大的组合
negotiation and do you think there's
谈判，你认为有吗？
room in that example of merging to model
合并模型的例子中的房间
this whole situation is an imperfect
这整个情况并不完美
information game or do you really want
信息游戏还是你真的想要
to consider it to be a perfect no that's
把 它看作是一个完美的 没有这
a good question yeah that's a good
一个好问题 是的 ，这是一个好的
question I'm paid the price of assuming
问题我付出了 假设 的 代价
that you don't know everything yeah I
你什么都不知道我
don't know it's certainly much easier
不知道它 肯定 要容易得多
games with perfect information are much
完美 信息的 游戏 很多
easier so if you can get away with it
更容易，如果你可以逃脱 它
you should but if the real situation is
你应该，但如果真实的情况是
of imperfect information then you're
那么你就是不完美的信息
going to have to deal with in for
将不得不应对 的
imperfect information great so what
不完美的信息非常好
lessons have you learned the annual
你学到了一年一度的课程
computer poker competition an incredible
电脑扑克比赛令人难以置信
accomplishment of AI you know you look
AI的成就， 你知道你的样子
at the history of deep blue
在深蓝色的历史
go these kind of moments when I stepped
走的时候去这些时刻
up in an engineering effort and a
在工程方面的努力和
scientific effort combined to beat the
科研工作相结合，打
best human players so what do you take
最好的人类球员所以你采取什么
away from this whole experience what
离 这整个过程是什么
have you learned about designing it has
你有没有了解它的设计？
systems that play these kinds of games
玩这类游戏的系统
and what does that mean for sort of AI
这对于某种 AI 来说意味着什么
in general for the future of IAI
一般来说， IAI 的未来
development yeah so that's a good
发展是的 ，这是一个很好的
question so there's so much to say about
问题所以有这么多谈谈
it I do like this type of performance
我喜欢这种 表现
oriented research although in my group
虽然 在 我的小组中， 但是 有 针
we go all the way from like idea to
我们 从同样的想法 一路 走到
theory to experiments to big system
理论对大系统的实验
fielding the commercialization so we
我们实现了商业化
spend that spectrum but I think that in
花费那个频谱， 但 我 认为
a lot of situations in AI you really
你真的在AI 很多情况下
have to build the big systems and
必须建立大系统和
evaluate them at a scale before you know
在 你知道 之前 按比例评估它们
what works and doesn't and we've seen
什么有用，有没有，我们已经看到了
that in the computational game theory
在 计算博弈论中
community that there are a lot of
社区，有很多
techniques that look good in the small
小巧的技术
but then they cease to look good in the
但随后他们就不再那么好看了
large and we've also seen that there are
大，我们也看到有
a lot of techniques that look superior
许多技术看起来 更优越
in theory and I really mean in terms of
从理论上讲，我的意思是
convergence rates better like
收敛速度一样好
first-order methods better convergence
一阶方法更好地收敛
rates like the CFR based based
基于CFR的费率
algorithms yet the CFR pay based
算法但CFR 基于薪酬
algorithms are the fastest in practice
算法是在实践 中 发展最快
so it really tells me that you have to
所以它真的告诉我你必须这样做
test this in reality the theory isn't
在现实中测试这个理论并非如此
tight enough if you will to tell you
如果你愿意告诉你，那就够了
which algorithms are better than the
哪种算法优于
others and you have to look at these
其他人，你 必须看看这些
things that in the large because any
在 大的东西， 因为任何
sort of projections you do from the
你做的一些预测
small and at least in this domain be
很小， 至少在这个领域
very misleading so that that's kind of
非常误导所以那就是那种
from from a kind of science and
从 一种 科学和
engineering perspective from personal
个人的工程视角
perspective it's been just a wild
透视它 只是一个狂野的
experience in that with the first poker
与第一个扑克相关的经验
competition the first or first brains
竞争第一 或第一 脑筋
versus AI man-machine poker competition
与AI人机扑克比赛
that we organized there had been by the
我们组织的那里曾经有过
way for other poker games there had been
曾经有过其他扑克游戏的方式
previous competitions but this was for
之前的比赛，但这是为了
heads up No Limit this was the first and
抬头 无限制 这是第一次和
I probably became the most hated person
我可能成了最讨厌的人
in the world of Poker and I didn't mean
在扑克界 ，我不是故意的
to III size that they cracked in the
它们破裂的 III 尺寸
game for yeah it was a lot of people
游戏是的，这是很多 人
felt that it was a real
觉得这是一个真正的
threat to the whole game the whole
对整个游戏 的整体威胁
existence of the game if AI becomes
如果AI成为游戏的存在
better than humans people would be
比人类更好的人 会
scared to play poker because there are
害怕，因为有打扑克
the superhuman AI is running around
超人AI正在四处奔波
taking their money and you know all of
拿走他们的钱，你知道所有的
that so so I just it's just really
所以我 只是它真的
aggressive just in the comments were
只是在评论中 积极进取
super aggressive I got everything
超级好斗我得到了一切
it's just short of death threats do you
它只是没有 死亡威胁你
think the same was true for chess
国际象棋认为同样如此
because right now they just completed
因为现在他们刚刚完成
the World Championships and chess and
世界锦标赛和 国际象棋和
humans just started ignoring the fact
人类 刚开始忽视 这个事实
that there's AI systems now that I'll
我 现在有AI系统
perform humans and they still enjoy the
执行人类，他们仍然享受
game is still a beautiful game that's
游戏仍然是一个美丽的游戏
what I think yeah and I think the same
我的想法是的，我也是如此
thing happens in poker and so I didn't
事情发生 在扑克中，所以我没有
think of myself as somebody was gonna
把自己想象成有人会
kill the game and I don't think I did
杀死游戏，我 不 认为我做了
yeah I've really learned to love this
是的我真的学会了喜欢 这个
game I wasn't a poker player before but
游戏我之前 不是 扑克玩家
learn so many new ones is about it from
从中学到很多新东西
these AIS and they've really changed how
这些AIS ，他们真的改变 了
the game is played by the way so they
该游戏由使他们的方式 打
have these very Martian ways of playing
有这些非常火星的游戏方式
poker and the top humans are now
扑克和顶级人类现在
incorporating those types of strategies
纳入这些类型的战略
into their own play so if anything to me
进入自己的游戏，如果对我有任何意义
our work has made poker a richer more
我们的工作让扑克 更富有
interesting game for humans to play not
有趣的游戏让人类不玩
something that is gonna steer him as
会引导他的东西
away from it entirely just a quick
远离它完全只是一个快速
comment and something you said which is
评论和你 说的是什么
if I may say so in academia is a little
如果我可以在学术界说这么一点
bit rare sometimes it's pretty brave to
有点罕见有时它非常勇敢
put your ideas to the test in the way
把你的想法 ，以测试 的方式
you described
你描述过
saying that sometimes good ideas don't
说有时好的想法 不会
work when you actually try to apply them
当你真正尝试应用它们时工作
at scale and so where does that come
在规模，所以它来了
from I mean what if you could do a
从我的 意思是如果你 能做到的
advice for people what what drives you
为人们提供什么促使你的建议
in that sense were you always this way I
从那个意义上说，你总是这样我
mean it takes a brave person I guess is
意味着我认为这需要一个勇敢的 人
what I'm saying to test their ideas and
我在说什么来 测试他们的 想法和
to see if this thing actually works
看看 这件事是否真的有效
against human top human players and so
对抗人类顶级人类玩家等等
on yeah I don't know about brave but it
是的，我不知道 勇敢，但它
takes a lot of work it takes a lot of
需要花费大量的工作 才能 完成
work and a lot of time to organize do
工作和 很多 时间 组织起来
make something big and to organize an
做一些大事并组织一个
event and stuff like that and what
事件和类似的东西和什么
drives you in that effort because you
因为 你， 你会为此付出努力
could still I would argue get a best
我仍然可以争辩得到最好的
paper award and nips as you did in 17
像你在17年所做的那样，获得纸质奖励和奖励
without doing this that's right yes
没有做到这一点是对的
and so so in general I believe it's very
所以总的来说我相信 它非常
important to do things in in the real
在真实中做事很重要
world and at scale and that's really
世界和规模 ，这是 真的
where the the the pudding if you will
如果你 愿意 的话布丁在哪里
proof is in the pudding that's what
布丁的证据是什么
that's where it is in this particular
就是这个特殊的地方
case it was kind of a competition
情况下， 它是 一种竞争的
between different groups and for many
在不同的群体 和许多人之间
years as to who can be the first one to
关于谁可以成为第一个
beat the top humans that heads up No
击败了排名靠前的顶级人物
Limit Texas Hold'em so it became it
限制德州扑克如此成为它
became kind of a like a competition who
变得有点像竞争者
can get there yeah so a little friendly
可以到达那里， 所以有点友好
competition could be I can do wonders
竞争可能是我可以创造奇迹
for progress yes so the topic of
因为进步是的所以主题是
mechanism design which is really
机制设计真的
interesting also kind of new to me
对我来说也很有趣
except as an observer if I don't know
如果我不知道，作为观察员除外
politics and any I'm an observer of
政治和任何我的观察员
mechanisms but you write in your paper
机制，但你写在你的论文
an automated mechanism design that I
我 自动化的 机制设计
quickly read so mechanism design is
快速阅读所以 机制设计是
designing the rules of the game so you
设计游戏规则 让 你
get a certain desirable outcome and you
得到一定的理想结果和你
have this work on doing so in an
对 在 这样做这项工作
automatic fashion as opposed to
自动时尚而不是
fine-tuning it so what have you learned
微调它所以你学到了什么
from those efforts if you look say I
从 这些 努力，如果你看 我说
don't know at complex it's like our
不知道复杂， 它就像我们的
political system can we design our
我们可以 设计政治制度
political system to have in an automated
政治制度有自动化
fashion to have outcomes that we want
时尚有我们想要的结果
can we design something like traffic
我们可以 设计类似交通的东西
lights to be smart where it gets
灯光要聪明才能到达
outcomes that we want so what are the
我们想要的结果是什么
lessons you draw from that work yeah so
教训你的工作啊 所以画
I still very much believe in the
我还是很相信
automated mechanism design direction yes
自动化机制设计方向是
but it's not a panacea
但它不是灵丹妙药
there are impossibility results in
有不可能的结果
mechanism design saying that there is no
机制设计说 没有
mechanism that accomplishes objective X
完成目标X的机制
in Class C so so they it's not gonna
在C 级 ，所以他们不会
there's no way using any mechanism
没有 办法 使用任何机制
design tools manual or automated
设计工具手册或自动化
to do certain things in mechanism design
在 机制设计中做某些事情
he can't describe that again so meaning
他 无法再描述 那么多的含义
there it's impossible to achieve that
在那里 实现 这一 目标 是 不可能的
yeah yes it was likely impossible so so
是的，这 可能是不可能的
so these are these are not statements
所以这些都不是 陈述
about human ingenuity who might come up
关于可能会出现的人类聪明才智
with something smart these are proofs
聪明的东西，这些都是证明
that if you wanna accomplish properties
如果你想完成的属性
X in Class C that is not to oppose with
X在C类中为不 与 对 置
any mechanism the good thing about
任何机制都是好事
automated mechanism design is that we're
自动化机制设计是我们的
not really designing for a class we're
我真的没有为一个班级设计
designing for specific settings at the
设计特定的设置
time so even if there's an impossibility
即使有 不可能的时间也是如此
result for the whole class it just
它只是整个班级的 结果
doesn't mean that all of the cases in
并不意味着所有的案件
the class are impossible it just means
这个课程不可能 只是意味着
that some of the cases are impossible so
有些情况是不可能的
we can actually carve these islands of
我们 实际上 可以 雕刻这些岛屿
possibility within these known
这些已知的可能性
impossible classes and we've actually
不可能的课程，我们实际上
done that so what one of the famous
这样做有 什么名气呢
results in mechanism design is a Meyer
机制设计的结果是 迈耶
sham set its weight theorem for pi Roger
sham 为 pi Roger 设定 了权重定理
Myerson and Mark Satterthwaite from 1983
1983年， Myerson和Mark Satterthwaite
so it's an impossibility of efficient
所以这是不可能有效的
trade under imperfect information we
在不完美的信息下交易我们
show that you can in many settings avoid
表明你可以在许多设置中避免
that and get the efficient trade anyway
无论如何，并获得有效的贸易
depending on how they design the game
取决于他们 如何 设计游戏
okay so depending how you design the
好吧，这取决于你如何设计
game and of course it's not it doesn't
游戏，当然不是没有
in any way any way contradict to
以任何方式任何 方式 对 矛盾
impossibility result or impossibility
不可能的结果或不可能性
results is still there but it just finds
结果仍然存在，但它 只是发现
spots within this impossible class where
这是不可能的所在班级内 点
in those spots you don't have time
在那些景点，你没有 时间
possibility sorry if I'm going a bit
可能 对不起，如果我走了一会儿
philosophical but what lessons you draw
哲学但是你 吸取了 什么教训
towards like I mentioned politics or
就像我提到政治或
human interaction and designing
人际互动和设计
mechanisms for outside of just these
外面的机制只是这些
kinds of trading or auctioning or purely
各种交易或拍卖或纯粹
formal games our human interaction like
正式游戏我们的人际互动 就像
a political system what how do you think
一个政治体系你怎么想
it's applicable to yeah politics or to
它适用于耶和华政治 或
business to negotiations these kinds of
商业谈判这些
things
事
designing rules that have certain
设计具有一定的规则
outcomes yeah yeah I do think so have
结果是啊是啊我是这么认为的 有
you seen success that successfully done
你看到成功完成的成功
yes and really oh you mean mechanism
是的，真的哦，你的意思是机制
design or automated make automated
设计或自动化自动化
mechanism design but so so mechanism
机制设计但 机制如此
design itself has had fairly limited
设计本身已经相当有限
success so far there are certain cases
到目前为止 成功 有一定的情况
but most of the real-world situations
但大多数 的 现实情况
are actually not sound from a mechanism
实际上并不是来自机制的声音
design perspective even in those cases
即使在 那些情况下， 设计视角
where they've been designed by very
它们是 由非常 设计 的
knowledgeable mechanism design people
知识渊博的机制设计人
the people are typically just taking
人们通常只是走
some insights from the theory and
理论和理论的一些见解
applying those insights into the real
将这些见解应用到真实中
world rather than applying the
世界而 不是应用
mechanisms directly so one famous
机制直接让人着名
example of is the FCC spectrum auctions
FCC频谱拍卖的例子
so I've also had a small role in that
所以我也有 在 一个小 角色
and very good economists have been where
非常好的经济学家一直在哪里
excellent economists have been working
优秀的经济学家一直在努力
on that with no game theory yet the
在没有博弈论的情况下
rules that are designed in practice
在实践中设计的规则
they're they're such that bidding
他们就是这样 竞标
truthfully is not the best strategy
说实不是最好的策略
usually mechanism design we try to make
通常我们试图制作机制设计
things easy for the participants so
这对参与者来说很容易
telling the truth is the best strategy
说实话是最好的策略
but but even in those very high stakes
但 即使在那些非常高的赌注中
auctions where you have tens of billions
你有数百亿的拍卖
of dollars worth of expect from being
美元值得期待的美元
auctioned truth-telling is not the best
拍卖真相并不是最好的
strategy and by the way nobody knows
策略，顺便说一句，没有人知道
even a single optimal bidding strategy
甚至是单一的最优竞价策略
for those auctions what's the challenge
对于那些拍卖 来说，挑战是什么
of coming up with an optimum because
的 未来与 最佳 的 ，因为
there's a lot of players and there's a
有很多球员， 而且有一个
lot of players but many items for sale
很多球员，但很多物品 待售
and the these mechanisms are such that
而 这些机制就是这样的
even with just two items or one item
即使 只有两个项目或一个项目
bidding truthfully wouldn't be the best
如实竞价并不是最好的
strategy if you look at the history of
如果你 看一下这个 历史的策略
AI it's marked by seminal events and
人工智能它的标志是开创性事件和
alphago being a world champion human go
alphago是世界冠军人类
player I would put librettist winning
球员我会把librettist赢了
the heads of no-limit hold'em as one of
无限额德州扑克为一体的 头
such event thank you and what do you
这样的事件 谢谢你， 你做了 什么
think
认为
is the next such event whether it's in
是下一个这样的事件是否在
your life or in the broadly AI community
你的生活 或广泛的 AI社区
that you think might be out there that
你认为可能是在那里 ，
would surprise the world so that's a
会让世界感到惊讶， 所以这是一个
great question and I don't really know
很好的问题 ，我真的不知道
the answer in terms of game solving hits
在 游戏 中 解决命中方面的答案
up No Limit Texas Hold'em really was the
无限德州德州扑克真的是
one remaining widely agreed-upon
一个仍然广泛同意的
benchmark so that was the big milestone
基准，这是一个重要的里程碑
now are there other things yes certainly
现在还有其他事情肯定
there are but there there is not one
但是那里没有一个
that the community has kind of focused
社区有点专注
on so what could be other things there
就这么，这可能是其他的东西 存在
are groups working on StarCraft there
是在星际争霸在那里工作组
are groups working on dota2 these are
上DOTA2这 是工作组
video games yes or you could have like
视频游戏是或者你可能喜欢
diplomacy or Hanavi you know things like
外交或哈纳维你知道的事情
that these are like recreational games
这些都像休闲娱乐游戏
but none of them are really acknowledged
但 他们都 没有 得到真正的承认
that's kind of the main next challenge
这是下 一个主要挑战
problem like chess or go or heads-up No
像国际象棋或去或 单挑的问题
Limit Texas Hold'em was so I don't
限制德州扑克是我不这样做的
really know in the game solving space
真的知道在游戏中解决空间
what is or what will will be the next
接下来是什么或 将会 是 什么
benchmark
基准
I hope kind of hope that there will be a
我希望有希望会有一个
next benchmark because really the
下一个基准， 因为真的
different groups working on the same
不同人群对同一工作
problem really drove these application
问题确实推动了这些应用
independent techniques for put very
非常独立的技术
quickly over ten years do you think
你认为很快就会超过十年
there's an open problem that excites you
有一个令你兴奋的开放性问题
that you start moving away from games
你开始 远离游戏了
into real world games like say the stock
进入现实世界的游戏，比如说股票
market trading yeah that's that's kind
市场交易是的那就是那种
of how I am so I am probably not going
怎么我 ，所以我可能不会
to work as hard on these recreational
努力工作这些娱乐活动
benchmarks I'm doing to startups on game
基准测试我正在为初创公司做游戏
solving technology strategic machine and
解决技术战略机器和
strategy robot and we're really
战略机器人，我们真的
interested in pushing this stuff into
有兴趣推动 这些 东西
practice what do you think would be
练习你认为会 是什么
really you know a powerful result that
真的，你知道一个强大的结果
would be surprising that would be if you
会是令人惊讶的 ，如果你
can say I mean you know five years ten
可以说我的意思是你知道五年十
years from now something that
几年后的 事情
statistically you would say is not very
统计上你会说不是很好
likely but if there's a breakthrough
可能但是 如果有突破的话
what achieve yeah so I think that
实现什么啊，所以我认为 ，
overall we're in a very different
总的来说， 我们的情况非常不同
situation in game theory than we are in
博弈论的情况比我们所处
let's say machine learning yes
让我们说机器学习是的
so in machine learning it's a fairly
所以在机器学习中它是公平的
mature technology and it's very broadly
成熟的技术，而且非常广泛
applied and proven success in the real
应用并证明了真实的成功
world in game solving there are almost
游戏解决的世界几乎都有
no applications yet
还没有申请
we have just become superhuman which
我们刚刚成为超人
machine learning you could argue
机器 学习你可以争辩
happened in the 90s if not earlier and
发生在90年代， 如果不是更早 和
at least some supervised learning at
至少有一些监督学习
certain complex supervised learning
某些复杂的监督学习
applications
应用
now I think a next challenge problem I
现在我认为下一个挑战问题我
know you're not asking about this way
知道你不是问 这样
you're you're asking about the
你是在问这个问题
technology breakthrough but I think the
技术突破， 但我认为
big big breakthrough is to be able to
大大的突破是要能够
show it hey maybe most of let's say
显示它嘿可能大多数让我们说
military planning or most of business
军事计划或大部分业务
strategy will actually be done
策略实际上会完成
strategically using computational game
策略性地使用计算游戏
theory that that's what I would like to
理论认为， 这是我想什么
see as a next five or ten year goal
看作下一个 五年或十年的 目标
maybe you can explain to me again
也许你可以 再次 向 我 解释
forgive me if this is an obvious
如果 这是 显而易见的，请 原谅我
question but you know machine learning
问题， 但你知道机器学习
methods neural networks are suffer from
方法神经网络受到影响
not being transparent not being
没有透明度
explainable a game theoretic methods you
可解释的游戏理论方法 你
know Nash equilibria do they generally
他们一般都知道纳什均衡
when you see the different solutions are
当你看到不同的 解决方案 时
they when you talk about military
他们当你 谈论 军事
operations are they once you see the
一旦你看到了它们就是它们的操作
strategies do they make sense that they
策略做他们有意义 ，他们
explainable or do they suffer from the
可解释还是他们从遭受
same problems as neural networks do so
与神经网络相同的问题也是如此
that's that's a good question I would
这就是我想要的一个好问题
say a little bit yes and no and what I
说一点 是，不，我是什么
mean by that is that these games are
由意思是说， 这些游戏
ethic strategies let's say Nash
伦理战略让我们 说纳什
equilibrium it has provable properties
平衡它具有可证明的特性
so it's unlike let's say deep learning
所以它与深度学习不同
where you kind of cross your fingers
你在哪里交叉你的手指
hopefully it'll work and then after the
希望它能够工作，然后继续工作
fact when you have the weights you're
事实上， 当你 有权重 时
still crossing your fingers and I hope
我希望还在你的手指上
it will work here you know that the
它会在这里工作你知道的
solution quality is there this provable
解决方案的质量是可以证明的
or Souls from quality guarantees now
或现在质量保证的灵魂
that doesn't necessarily mean that the
这并不一定 意味着
strategies are human understandable
策略是人类可以理解的
that's a whole other problem so that's
这是一个整体的其他 问题，所以 这是
also I think it deep learning and
我认为它深入学习和
computational game theory are in the
计算博弈论在
same boat in that sense that both are
在这个意义上同样的船， 两者都是
difficult to understand but at least the
难以理解，但至少是
game theoretic techniques they have this
游戏理论技巧他们有这个
guarantees of guarantee quality so did
保证质量的保证也是如此
you see business operations to achieve
你看到要实现的业务运营
your corporations or even military in
你的公司甚至军队
the future being at least the strong
未来至少是强者
candidates being proposed by automated
候选人是自动提出的
systems do you see that yeah I do I do
系统你看到我做 我做的
but that's more of a really belief than
但这更像是一种真正的信仰
a substantiated fact depending on where
一个证实的事实取决于在哪里
you land and optimism or pessimism
你降落，乐观或悲观
that's a relief to me that's an exciting
这是一种 解脱 ，我 认为是一个令人兴奋
future especially if they're provable
未来，特别是 如果他们是 可证明的
things
事
in terms of optimality so looking into
在最优性方面如此调查
the future there's a a few folks worried
未来有一些人担心
about the especially you look at the
特别是你看看
game of poker which is probably one of
扑克游戏，可能是其中之一
the last benchmarks in terms of games
游戏 方面的最后一个基准
being solved they they worry about the
正在解决他们担心的问题
future and the existential threats of
未来和存在的威胁
artificial intelligence so the negative
人工智能 如此消极
impact in whatever form on society is
对社会的任何形式的影响是
that something that concerns you as much
那些与你有关的东西
are you more optimistic about the
你更看好
positive impacts of AI oh I am much more
AI的积极影响哦，我 更多
optimistic about the positive impacts so
对这种积极影响持乐观态度
just in my own work what we've done so
在我自己的工作中我们做了什么
far we run the nationwide kidney
我们 在 全国范围内 运行 肾脏
exchange hundreds of people are walking
交换数百人正在走路
around alive today who would it be and
围绕今天还活着会是谁 和
it's increased employment you had you
你拥有 的就业机会增加 了
have a lot of people now running kidney
已经有很多 人现在正在运行肾
changes and at the transplant centers
变化和移植 中心
interacting with the kidney exchange you
与肾脏相互作用交换你
have extra surgeons nurses
有额外的外科医生护士
anesthesiologists hospitals all of that
麻醉师医院所有这些
as so so employment is increasing from
因此就业增加了
that and the world is becoming a better
那个和世界 变得 更好
place
地点
another example is combinatorial
另一个例子是组合
sourcing auctions we did 800 large-scale
采购拍卖我们做了 800大规模
combinatorial sourcing auctions from
组合采购拍卖
2001 to 2010 in a previous startup of
2001年至2010年在之前的 创业公司
mine called combine it and we increased
我打电话给 它 ，我们 增加了
the supply chain efficiency on that
供应链的 效率
sixty billion dollars of spend by twelve
十二点 六十亿美元的 花费
point six percent so that's over six
指出 百分之 六 ，超过六
billion dollars of efficiency
十亿美元的效率
improvement in the world and this is
改善世界，这是
also like shifting value from somebody
也 喜欢从某人那里转移价值
to somebody else just efficiency
对其他人来说 只是效率
improvement like in trucking less empty
像卡车运输中的改进那么空洞
driving so there's less waste less
驾驶所以有更少的浪费少
carbon footprint and so on it's a huge
碳足迹等等， 这是一个巨大的问题
positive impact in the near term but
但在短期内会产生积极影响
sort of to stay in it for a little
有点呆在里面
longer because I think game theory is a
更长的因为我认为博弈论是一个
role to play here well let me actually
在这里发挥的作用让我 真的
come back and tell you this is one thing
回来 告诉你这是一回事
I think Asia is also going to make the
我认为亚洲也将会成功
world much safer so so so that's another
世界更加安全，所以那是另一个
aspect that often gets overlooked well
经常被忽视的方面良好
let me ask this question maybe you can
让我问 这个问题，也许你可以
speak to the the safer so I talked to
说话更安全，所以我跟他说话
max tegmark is do a Russell who are very
马克斯·泰格马克是做罗素谁是 非常
concerned about
关注
the resume yeah and often the concern is
简历是的，往往是关注
about value misalignment so AI systems
关于价值不对准所以AI系统
basically working operating towards
基本上是在努力工作
goals that are not the same as human
与人类不同的目标
civilization human beings so it seems
文明人 似乎如此
like game theory has a role to play
喜欢博弈论可以发挥作用
there to to make sure the values are
那里要 确保价值观
aligned with human beings I don't know
与人类保持一致我不知道
if that's how you think about it if not
如果这是你如何看待它，如果不
how do you think AI might help with this
你怎么认为AI可能会对此有所帮助
problem how do you think a i'ma make the
问题你 觉得 我 怎么做 的？
world safer yeah I think this value
世界更安全是的我认为这个价值
misalignment is a fairly theoretical
错位是一个相当理论上的问题
worry and I haven't really seen it in it
担心，我还没有真正看到它
because I do a lot of real applications
因为我做了很多真正的应用程序
I don't see it anywhere
我没有看到它 的任何地方
the closest I've seen it was the
我见过的最接近的是
following type of mental exercise really
以下类型的心理锻炼真的
where I had this argument in the late
我迟到了这个论点
80s when we were building these
我们 建造这些时的80年代
transportation optimization systems and
运输优化系统和
somebody had heard that it's a good idea
有人听说这是个好主意
to have high utilization of assets so
有资产的利用率高，从而
they told me that hey why don't you put
他们告诉我， 嘿，你为什么不放
that as objective and we didn't even
这是客观的，我们甚至没有
pull it as an objective because I just
把它作为一个目标，因为 我只是
showed him it you know if you had that
告诉他你知道你有 没有
as your objective the solution would be
作为你的目标，解决方案将是
to load your trucks full and driving
装满 你的 卡车 并开车
circles nothing would ever get delivered
圈子什么都得不到
you'd have a hundred percent utilization
你有百分之百的利用率
so yeah I know this phenomenon I've
所以，我知道这个现象
known this for over 30 years in but I've
我已经知道 了30多年 了
never seen it actually be a problem
从未见过它实际上是一个问题
reality in reality and yes if you have
现实中的 现实，如果你有，那就是
the wrong objective the AI will optimize
AI将优化的错误目标
that to the hilt and it's gonna fit more
那个刀柄，它 会适合 更多
than some human who's kind of trying to
比一些人 试图做的那样
so within a half-baked way with some
所以用一些半生不熟的方式
human insight to but I just haven't seen
人类的洞察力，但我只是没有见过
that materialize in practice there's
在实践中Materialise的 有
this gap that you actually put your
这个差距， 你实际上 把你的
finger on very clearly just now between
刚才之间的手指上很清楚
theory and reality that's very difficult
理论和现实非常困难
to put into words I think it's what you
用语言表达我认为这就是 你
can theoretically imagine the worst
理论上可以想象最坏的情况
possible case or even yeah I mean bad
可能的情况，甚至是的，我的意思是坏
cases and what usually happens in
案件和通常发生的事情
reality so for example to me maybe it's
现实， 所以例如对我来说也许就是 这样
something you can comment on
你可以评论的东西
having grown up and I had grew up in the
我 已经长大了， 而且我 已经长大了
Soviet Union you know there's currently
苏联，你知道目前
10,000 nuclear weapons in the world and
万个核武器 世界 ，
for many decades it's theoretically
几十年来 它在理论上
surprising to me that the nuclear war is
令我惊讶的 是核战争
not broken out do you think about this
没有爆发你觉得这个吗？
aspect from a game theoretic perspective
从 博弈论的角度来看
in general why is that true why in
一般来说为什么这是真的 为什么
theory you could see how things would go
理论上，你可以看到怎么会事
terribly wrong and somehow yet they have
非常错误，不知何故他们有
not yeah how do you think so so I do
不是的，你怎么这么认为 我这样做
think that about that a lot I think the
想了 好久好久我觉得
biggest two threats that we're facing as
我们面临的两大威胁
mankind one is climate change and the
人类是气候变化和气候变化
other is nuclear war so I saw so those
另一个是核战争， 所以我看到了那些
are my main two worries that they're
他们担心的主要是两个问题
worried about and I've tried to do
担心，我试图 这样做
something about climate I thought about
一些关于 气候我想过
trying to do something for climate
试图为气候做点什么
change twice actually before two of my
实际上 在 我的两个 之前改变了两次
startups had actually commissioned
创业公司实际上已经委托了
studies of what we could do on those
什么，我们能在 这些做研究
things and we didn't really find a sweet
事情我们并没有真正 找到甜蜜
spot but I'm still keeping an eye out on
地方 ，但我还留着 一只眼睛 上
that if there's something where we could
如果有什么东西在那里我们 可以
actually provide a market solution or
实际上提供 市场解决方案或
optimization solution or some other
优化解决方案或其他一些
technology solution to problems right
技术解决问题的权利
now
现在
like for example pollution critic
比如污染评论家
markets was what we were looking at then
市场是我们当时看到的
and it was much more the lack of
而且缺乏更多
political will by those markets were not
这些市场的政治意愿不是
so successful rather than bad market
如此成功而不是糟糕的市场
design so I could go in and make a
设计所以我可以进去做一个
better market design but that wouldn't
更好的市场设计但不会
really move the needle on the world very
真正使针 对 世界很
much if there's no political will and in
很多， 如果没有政治 意愿和
the u.s. you know the market at least
美国你至少知道市场
the Chicago market was just shut down
芝加哥市场刚刚关闭
and and so on so it and then it doesn't
等等它然后它 没有
really help create your market design
真的有助于创造您的市场设计
was there any nuclear side it's more so
是否有任何核方面更是如此
global warming is more encroaching
全球变暖更加蚕食
problem you know nuclear weapons have
你知道核武器的问题
been here it's an obvious problem has
在这里这是一个明显的问题
just been sitting there so how do you
刚刚 坐在 那里你怎么样
think about what is the mechanism design
想想机制设计是什么
there that just made everything seem
只是让一切看起来都在那里
stable and are you still extremely
稳定，你还是非常
worried I am still extremely worried so
担心我 仍然 非常担心
you probably know the simple game theory
你可能知道简单的博弈论
of mad so solar so this was a mutually
如此 太阳的疯狂， 所以这是一个相互的
assured destruction and it's like it
确保破坏，它就像它
doesn't require any computation with
不需要任何计算
small matrices you can actually convince
你可以 说服的小矩阵
yourself that the game is such that
你自己认为游戏就是这样
nobody wants to initiate yeah that's a
没有人想要发起是的，这是一个
very coarse-grained analysis and it
非常粗粒度的分析和它
really works in a situation where you
真的适用于 你 的情况
have two superpowers or small number of
有两个超级大国或少数
superpowers now things are very
超级大国 现在的事情非常好
different you have a smaller nuke so the
不同你有一个较小的核武所以
threshold of initiating is smaller and
启动阈值较小
you have smaller countries and non non
你有较小的国家和非非国家
nation actors who make it Nokes and so
成为Nokes的国家演员等等
on so it's I think it's riskier now than
所以我觉得它现在风险更大
it was maybe ever before and what idea
这可能是以前和想法
application by I you've talked about a
我申请你已经谈过 了
little bit but what is the most exciting
点点 ，但什么是最令人兴奋的
to you right now
现在给你
I mean you you're here at nips europe's
我的意思是你在nips 欧洲的那里
now you have a few excellent pieces of
现在你有一些优秀的作品
work but what are you thinking into the
工作，但你在想什么呢？
future with several companies you're
你和几家公司的未来
doing what's the most exciting thing or
做什么是最令人兴奋的事情或
one of the exciting things the number
数字令人兴奋的事情之一
one thing but for me right now is coming
有一件事， 但对我来说， 现在来了
up with these scalable techniques for
这些可扩展的技术
game solving and applying them into the
游戏解决并将它们应用到游戏中
real world they're still very interested
现实世界他们仍然 非常感兴趣
in market design as well and we're doing
在市场设计方面我们也在做
that in the optimized markets but I'm
在 优化的市场，但我
most interested if number one right now
最感兴趣的是现在的第一名
is strategic machine strategy robots
是战略机器战略机器人
getting that technology out there and
获得该技术在那里 ，
seeing as you were in the trenches doing
看到你在 战壕里 做的事情
applications what needs to be actually
应用程序需要实际的东西
filled what technology gap still need to
填补 了 仍然需要的 技术 差距
be filled so it's so hard to just put
被填补所以 很难放到
your feet on the table and imagine what
你的脚在 桌子上，想象一下
needs to be done but when you're
需要 做 的 事情，但是当你
actually doing real applications the
实际做真正的应用程序
applications tell you what needs to be
应用程序告诉你什么需要是
done and I really enjoy that interaction
完成了，我真的很喜欢 这种互动
is it a challenging process to apply
申请是 一个具有挑战性的过程
some of the stay the are techniques
一些留下来的技术
you're working on and and having the
你正在努力并拥有
the various players in industry or the
不同的玩家在行业或
military or people who could really
军队或真正能够做到的人
benefit from it actually use it what's
受益于它实际上使用它是什么
that process like of you know in
像 你说的过程中知道
autonomous vehicles will work with
自动驾驶汽车将与之合作
automotive companies and they're in in
汽车公司和 他们在
many ways they're a little bit
很多方面他们都是一点点
old-fashioned it's difficult they really
老式的，他们真的很难
want to use this technology there's
想要使用这种技术
clearly will have a significant benefit
显然会有很大的好处
but the systems aren't quite in place to
但系统并不完善
easily have them integrated in terms of
很容易让他们在集成 方面
data in terms of compute in terms of all
根据所有数据计算的数据
these kinds of things so deuce is that
这类事情 ，所以活见鬼 的是，
one of the bigger challenges that you're
你遇到的更大挑战之一
facing and how do you tackle that
面对， 你 如何 解决这个问题
challenge yeah I think that's always a
挑战是啊 我 认为这总是一个
challenge that that's gonna slowness and
挑战那会慢下来
inertia really of let's do things the
惯性真的让我们做的事情
way we've always done it you just have
这样，我们一直在做它 ，你只 需要
to find the internal champions that the
找到内部 冠军的那个
customer who understand that hey things
了解嘿事的顾客
can't be the same way in the future
将来不可能是同样的方式
otherwise bad things are going to happen
否则会 发生 坏事
and it's in order most vehicles it's
这是 大多数车辆的 顺序
actually very interesting that the car
车 真的很有意思
makers are doing that then they're very
制造商正在这样做， 然后他们非常
traditional but at the same time you
传统， 但同时你
have tech companies who have nothing to
具有高科技公司谁也没什么
do with cars or transportation like
做 汽车或 交通工具
Google and Baidu really pushing on
谷歌和百度真的在推动
autonomous cars I find it fascinating
自动驾驶汽车我发现 它很吸引人
clearly you're super excited about
显然你非常 兴奋
actually these ideas having an impact in
实际上这些想法产生了影响
the world in terms of the technology in
在技​​术方面的世界
terms of ideas and research their
思想和研究的条款
directions that you're also excited
方向，你也很兴奋
about whether that's on the some of the
关于是否 就某些问题
approaches you talked about for the
接近你谈到的
imperfect information games whether it's
不完美的信息游戏是否是
applying deep learning just some of
应用深度学习只是一些
these problems is there something that
这些问题有一些问题
you're excited in in the research side
你 在研究方面 很 兴奋
of things yeah yeah lots of different
事情是 啊 是 啊 很多不同
things in the game solving so solving
游戏中的东西解决了所以解决
even bigger games games will you have
你会有更大的游戏吗？
more hidden action of the play your
更多隐藏的游戏动作你的
actions as well poker is a game where
扑克行动也是一场游戏
really the chance actions are hidden or
真的是隐藏的机会动作或
some of them are hidden but the player
其中一些是隐藏但玩家
actions are public
行动是公开的
the multiplayer games of various sorts
各种各样的多人游戏
collusion opponent exploitation all and
共谋 对手利用所有和
even longer games some games that
甚至更长的游戏 一些游戏
basically go forever but they're not
基本上是永远，但 他们 不是
repeated so seek extensive phone games
反复如此 寻求广泛的 手机游戏
that go forever whoa what what would
永远都会发生什么事情会发生什么
that even look like how do you represent
甚至看起来你怎么代表
that how do you solve that what's an
那你怎么 解决 什么是
example of a game like that or is this
像 这样 的游戏的例子或者是这样的
some of the stochastic games the imagine
一些 随机游戏的想象
let's say business strategy so it's and
让我们说商业策略吧
not just modeling like a particular
不只是像特定的 建模
interaction but thinking about the
交互但思考
business from here to eternity
从这里到永恒的生意
or I think or let's let's say military
或者我想或 让我们说军事
strategy so it's not like war is going
策略，让它不喜欢战争是 怎么回事
to go away how do you think about
离开你怎么想
military strategy that's going to go
军事战略即将 开始
forever how do you even model that how
永远你怎么样甚至模拟如何
do you know whether a move was good that
你知道 这一举动 是否 合适
you somebody made and and and so on so
你是谁制造的，依此类推
that that's kind of one direction I'm
那是我的一个方向
also very interested in learning much
对学习也很感兴趣
more scalable techniques for integer
整数的可扩展技术
programming so we had a nice email paper
编程所以我们有一个很好的 电子邮件纸
this summer on that for the first
今年夏天就是第一个
automated algorithm configuration paper
自动算法配置文件
that has theoretical generalization
这有理论上的概括
guarantees so if I see these many
如果我看到这么多，我会保证
training examples and I told my
培训实例， 我告诉我
algorithm in this way it's going to have
它会以这种方式运算
good performance on the real
真实的表现
distribution which have not seen so
没有见过的分布
which is kind of interesting that you
这对你来说很有意思
know algorithm configuration has been
知道算法配置已经
going on now for at least 17 years
现在至少 持续 了17年
seriously and there has not been any
认真地，没有任何
generalization theory before well this
在此之前的泛化理论
is really exciting and it's been it's a
真的很令人兴奋 ，而且一直都是
huge honor to talk to you thank you so
谈巨大的荣誉给你感谢你 这么
much to us thank you for bringing
我们非常感谢你 带来的
livadas to the world and all the great
livadas对世界和所有 伟大的
work you're done well thank you very
工作你做得 很好，非常感谢你
much it's been fun good questions
这很有趣，很好的问题
you
您